ETHAN CAFFREY

Sixmilebridge, Clare | P: +353 831550159 | ethancaff@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/ethan-caffrey-0b2976136 | Website: https://kahfree.github.io/

PERSONAL PROFILE

Aspiring software developer who is self-motivated with a passion for programming. Loves to work in a team. Has excellent critical thinking and analytical skills.

SUMMARY

Software development student at the Limerick Institute of Technology. Developed excellent critical thinking skills through my degree. Improved my soft skills significantly through my experience as a sales assistant at Dunnes Stores. My determination and dedication are highlighted by my achievement of a black belt in taekwondo. I have developed strong time management, team work, and critical thinking skills during my internship with ChannelAdvisor. Self-motivated. A Team Player with a strong work ethic.

EXPERIENCE

CHANNELADVISOR

Software Engineer Intern

Mar 2022 - Aug 2022

Limerick, Ireland

- Developed robust code to handle REST request and responses in C# and .NET
- Worked with Azure DevOps and to deliver CI/CD
- Followed agile workflow with scrum and sprint reviews
- Worked with javascript for frontend, specflow for testing, and redis for caching data.

DUNNES STORES

Sales Assistant

Shannon, Clare, Ireland

Mar 2021 - Dec 2021

- Delivering superb service by engaging with customers.
- Ensuring that visual and brand standards area maintained on the sales floor.
- Ensuring that promotional activity is delivered.
- Stock inventory to the shop floor.

FIVERR

Website Developer / Freelancer

July 2020 - Dec 2020

- Build website using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Work closely with client to collect requirements and ensure project quality.
- Understanding the importance of communication to build the project.
- Currently inactive to prioritise academic studies.

JOHNSON & JOHNSON

Hackathon Feb 2020

- Worked as a team to product a project under a time constraint
- Developed a Live Search of persistent data through combination of problem solving and teamwork.
- Learned the importance of reading documentation and writing good documentation for your code.
- Development using JavaScript, jQuery, and AJAX.

EDUCATION

LIMERICK INSTUITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY – Limerick, Ireland

BSc with Honours in Software Development Year 1 GPA: (80.66). Year 2 GPA: (85.08). Year 3 GPA: (80.2). 2019 - 2023

Modules for Year 1: Web Dev (98), Responsive Web Design (91), SQL fundamentals (74), introduction to databases (68), Computer Architecture (88), Operating Systems (74), Computer Mathematics (95), Structured programming (80), Object Oriented programming (73).

Modules for Year 2: Networking fundamentals (84), Software Development (80), Data Design and Programming (98), Discrete Mathematics (85), Data Structures and Algorithms (77), Object Oriented Theory and Programming (94), Real Time Embedded Systems (88), Software Testing (74), Data Driven Systems (92), Problem Solving with Data Structures (77), Internetworking (82), Applications Development (90).

Modules for Year 3: Work Placement (PS), Computer Science (68), Object Modelling & Design (74), Software Development Project (76), Secure Web Development (94), Applications Programming (89).

ADDITIONAL

Technical: SQL, PHP, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, C#, Python, C++, Git, Java **Certifications & Training:** C++ (Codecademy), Git (Codecademy), Command Line (Codecademy), SQL Fundamentals (SoloLearn).

PROJECTS

TREATY MARKET

- Responsive PHP webapp build using the Codelgniter framework.
- Functional e-commerce website with log in/ log out functionality and cart functionality.
- Admin account features with full Product CRUD.

TRAFFIC LIGHTS

- Constructed working simulation of traffic lights using an Arduino.
- Wired with LEDs and a light sensor, to change durations depending on the light level.
- Coded using the Arduino Programming language, which is based on C and C++.

STUDENT ASSIGNEMNT SYSTEM

- Developed a Student Assignment system using C# WinForms.
- Application has a Student, Lecturer, and Administrator dashboard.

References can be given upon request